[SOUND] So
那么
a second method for dimensionality reduction is multidimensional scaling.
第二个降维方法是多维缩放
It focuses on the distance between related items,
该方法关注相关数据项的间的距离
as opposed to their actual positions.
而不是它们的实际位置
So multidimensional scaling is a form of dimensionality reduction.
因此 多维缩放是 降维的一种方式
We previously looked at principle component analysis as a method for
我们之前了解了主成分分析法
dimensionality reduction.
和降维方法的课程
We have high dimensional data, and
我们有高维数据
we want to display it on a low dimensional display.
并且要将其在低维显示
On just using maybe two or three axes in order to be able to better visually
即使是高维数据 使用大概两个或者三个坐标
perceive the data, even if the data is high dimensional.
以便能够更好的以视觉感知数据
And so we've looked at this in terms of visualizing graphs.
我们从可视化图的角度讨论过
Graphs encode relationships between data points where the length of the edge is
视图对数据点之间的关系进行编码
irrelevant.
边长无关紧要。
But if we want to look at a graph where the length is relevant,
但是 如果我们要考虑一个视图 其边的长度是有意义的
we might want to look at ways of plotting the nodes of a graph or data,
我们或许会要考虑一些方式 基于数据点之间的关系 基于距离
based on the relationship between data points, based on distance.
来绘制一个图或者数据的节点
So that we can try to preserve the distance in, for example,
以便可以在低维中仍保持距离 例如
a low dimensional, a two dimensional visualization of high dimensional data.
高维数据的一个二维可视化
We may want the distance between data points in two dimensions to somehow
我们或许想用二维空间中 数据点之间的距离 以某种方式
indicate the distance between the data points in higher dimensions.
来标示出数据点间在更高维度中的距离
And so that sets up a metric MDS,
于是设定一个 MDS 的指标
metric multidimensional scaling where you try to preserve the distance between
用来测度在多维缩放中 将数据点显示在一个较低维的空间
data points even though you're displaying them at a lower dimensional space.
而仍试图保持数据点间的距离
So here's a nice example.
这里有一个很好的例子
We're not doing dimensionality reduction because we'll go from a two dimensional
这里我们没有进行降维 因为我们是从二维空间
space to a two dimensional space.
到二维空间
But it illustrates how we would compute a multidimensional scaling to try to
但是 它说明了如何计算多维缩放
preserve the distance between points.
以尽量保持点之间的距离
So here's distances between cities in the US, for example.
例如 这是美国城市间的距离
So we've got Boston, NYC, DC, Miami, Chicago, Seattle, SF, LA, and Denver.
我们有波士顿 纽约 哥伦比亚特区 迈阿密 芝加哥 西雅图 旧金山 洛杉矶 以及丹佛
And so the distance between, for example, Chicago and
例如 在这个例子中 芝加哥和纽约的距离
NYC would be 803 miles in this example.
应该是803英里
So the lower triangle of this data is showing the distance between
所以 该数据的下三角 显示的是每一行和每一列的城市
the city on the left and the city in the row, and the city in the column.
它们之间的距离
And so there'd be 0 distance between a city and itself.
所以 一个城市到自己的距离是 0
And this will be symmetric, so
而且 这是对称的
I haven't bothered to fill in the upper triangle of this matrix.
所以我没有费力去填写 这个矩阵的上三角
So given those distances, dij, between data points i and j,
那么根据这个距离 dij 第 i 和 j 个数据点之间的距离
between city i and city j, can we recover the positions of those cities?
即第 i 和 j 个城市之间的距离 我们能否找回这些城市的位置 ?
So I'm not taking the coordinates of those cities,
我没有用这些城市的坐标
I'm just taking the distances between those cities.
我只用这些城市间的距离
Basically taking a graph where I'm specifying the length of the edges between
基本上来说 是用一个图 来显示节点之间
the nodes.
边的长度
And then I want to find the positions of the nodes that satisfies
然后 我想要找到那些节点的位置
those edge lengths.
其满足那些边的长度
So we can do that by minimizing this function.
我们可以通过最小化这个函数做到
We basically take the distance between the two data points,
基本上 我们使用两个数据点之间的距离
and then we want to subtract their actual distance, and we want to minimize that.
然后 我们想要减去它们的实际距离 并且我们想要最小化这个差值
So if the distance between two data points equals the desired distance
于是 如果两个数据点间的距离
between those two data points, then this should be close to zero.
等于这两点的期望的距离 那么这个函数应该接近于零
And we square things here so that we keep everything positive so
然后 对这些取平方 以保证所有项都是正值
that negative values aren't messing up our minimization.
从而最小化不受负值所影响
So we can solve this with any number of non-linear optimization methods.
我们能使用任何非线性优化方法 求解这个最小化问题
In the example I'm going to describe, I solved it just using
在我将要描述的例子中 我求解最小化仅仅使用了
the Excel spreadsheet program with an optimizer plug-in.
Excel的一个优化插件
So here's the results that I got,
这是我得到的运行结果
I minimized that distance relationship between the actual
我最小化了从被最优化的变量 到期望距离
distance from my optimized variables and the desired distance.
之间的距离关系
And as you can see, things are obviously in the wrong place.
如你所见 这看起来明显不对
I've got the East Coast on the left and West Coast on the east, but
我得到的是 东海岸在左边 而西海岸在东边
that should still preserve distance.
但是 距离关系则是对的
And there's a few other differences,
这里还有一些其它的不同之处
but basically I've got this general east to west trend.
但总的来说 我得到了这个 从东到西的基本趋势
Seattle is above SF and LA, Denver is here, Chicago is where it's at.
西雅图在旧金山和洛杉矶的上面 丹佛在这里 芝加哥在它该在的地方
So I've preserved the distance of my
所以 我保持了那些点的距离
points even though I haven't preserved the exact geometry of the points.
即便我没能保持那些点的 绝对几何关系
And so this can be a useful layout method, especially for high dimensional data when
所以 这可以是一个有用的展示方法 特别是于对高维数据
you're trying to preserve the distances between the points without necessarily
当你试图保持点之间的距离
representing accurately their spatial configuration, their original coordinates.
但不需要精确地表示它们的空间布局 即其原始坐标
So we've thrown away the original coordinates of these points.
所以 我们扔掉了 这些点的原始坐标
And just using their distance relationship,
仅使用它们的距离关系
tried to preserve that in a reprojection, in this case in two dimensions.
试图在一个重新映射中保持它们的距离 如在这个二维空间的例子中
So there's all sorts of ways you can use MDS, multidimensional scaling.
有很多方式你可以使用 MDS（多维缩放）
You can visualize affinities between data points,
你可以可视化 数据点间相邻关系
areas of collaboration based on co-authorship of papers.
例如 基于文章的共同作者关系 确定的合作领域
If you're visualizing papers or the number of any other attributes two data
如果你在对论文 或者任何其它两个数据点
points might have in common, anything you can describe as a distance.
可能共有的属性进行可视化 这些都可以通过距离关系来表达
It doesn't have to be coordinate distance, it can be other similarities.
它不一定需要是坐标距离 它可以是其它相似的关系
It's used in human-computer interaction for
它被用在为用户界面设计的人机交互
user interface design to basically lay out buttons.
如基本的按钮位置摆放
If you have a dashboard with a lot of buttons, you can lay out the buttons by
如果你一个仪表板 上面有很多按钮 你可以这样摆放按钮
organizing them based on how similar the buttons are to a given task.
对给定任务来说 基于按钮有多相似来组织它们
And then,
然后呢
let multidimensional scaling compute the coordinates of where the buttons should be
让多维缩放 计算出 按钮应该放在什么坐标位置
located so that buttons that are used together are close to each other.
从而让一起被使用的按钮 彼此摆放的很近
And it's also used in marketing to create what are called perceptual maps
它也被用在市场营销中 用来生成感知图（perceptual maps）
that are based on survey data of what people think of different products,
该图是基于人们 对不同产品有什么想法
what attributes people assign to different products.
给不同产品赋予什么属性 等的调查数据
And then you can figure out what products are similar to other products and
然后 你就可以弄明白 什么产品和其它产品相似
create a map of products that way.
并且用这种方法生成一个关于那些产品的视图
So, multidimensional scaling is enabled by optimization.
所以 最优化使 多维缩放得以实现
You don't have to write your own optimization program,
你不用自己去写你的优化程序
you can use pre-existing optimization packages.
你可以使用现有的 最优化软件包
You just need something that's going to minimize a function, and so
你只需要某个最小化一个函数的东西
you need some form of non-linear minimization in an optimization package.
所以 你需要一个最优化软件包中 某种形式的非线性最小化
I found one that was enabled in Excel in order to do
我在Excel中找到了一个可用的 让我能展示
the example I described in the slides.
我在幻灯片中讲述的例子
[MUSIC]
[背景音乐] 翻译: RyukaSuu |审阅: 19waa Coursera Global Translator Community